

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

London, United Kingdom

🛮 +447386203123 | 💌 vov.dorosh@gmail.com | 🖸 sQverful | 🛅 volodymyr-dorosh | 📢 vov.dorosh

Summary.

Full Stack Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience in the tech industry. Specialize in building enterprise applications using Java, Spring, and React, opened for new technologies and programming languages. Generative AI enthusiast, writing a research paper about applying LLMs in the finance industry. Seeking a challenging project with a diverse and collaborative team.

Skills

Main Technology Java

Front-end React, Typescript, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, MUI

Spring Framework, Kubernetes, Docker, Hibernate, ActiveMQ, Kafka, Flyway, Liquibase, Maven, Gradle,

Dec. 2021 - Jul. 2024

Frameworks/Technologies Keycloak, Flowable BPMN, AWS, Grafana, Microservices, SOA

Elastik/Kibana/Logstash, Rest API, gRPC

Testing Tools JUnit, Mockito, Karate, Cucumber, Postman, Swagger, Chrome DevTools

Bug Tracking Tools Jira

Source Control Github, Gitlab, Bitbucket

CI/CD Jenkins, Gitlab Pipelines, ArgoCD **Databases** PostgreSQL, etcd, MongoDB

Languages Advanced in English, Intermediate in Polish, Native in Ukrainian

Experience

Symphony Solutions Lviv, Ukraine

JAVA SOFTWARE ENGINEER AT THE FOLLOWING PROJECTS:

SOFTWARE & PRE-SALES ENGINEER AT SYMPHONY CLOUD PROJECT

- Delivered new front-end pages using React, Typescript and MUI with functionality for managing infrastructures in the admin panel.
- Delivered a PoC of infrastructure deployment from a Jira ticket using AWS Lambda, Jira webhooks, Gitlab pipelines.
- Knowledge sharing: delivered and presented on topics: Top AI code assisting tools, writing unit tests with ChatGPT, C4 model, Service Mesh Solutions, Java 22 updates.
- · Authored tech articles for the marketing team: using ChatGPT for writing unit tests, Traefik service mesh overview.
- Technologies: AWS Lambda, Google Cloud, Terraform, Terragrunt, Helm, ArgoCD, Kubernetes, Go, gRPC, React, Typescript, MUI.
- · Links:
 - https://symphony-solutions.cloud/

SOFTWARE ENGINEER AT BYBLOS BANK

- Delivered an IT Assets Management Solution with an automatic diagram generation and a front-end statistics panel for the bank's CTO.
- Migrated a Java 8 application to a Spring MVC application with Java 17.
- Integrated the application with the bank's Jira Assets API.
- Developed new logic for generating diagrams of the entire bank's IT infrastructure, making diagrams interactive and user-friendly.
- Implemented unit tests, increased code coverage to 85%.
- Technologies: Java, Spring MVC, Bootstrap, Jira Assets API, Structurizr, Docker, AWS, S3, EC2.

JAVA MENTOR AT LOGOS IT ACADEMY

- Mentored a Java Developer at IT school course during bench period at Symphony Solutions, all received funds donated to charity.
- Delivered Java Core lectures: Data types, OOP, Collections, Multi-threading, Exception handling.
- Prepared tests & reviewed students' code, providing constructive feedback and guidance.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER AT HANSECOM PROJECT

- Developed an urban mobility platform for EU & US mobility service providers with millions of users.
- Implemented role-based security for back-end application.
- Delivered a new microservice integrated with Flowable BPMN engine, enabling support for business process management in the admin panel.
- Delivered a new microservice for payments management.
- Developed new logic for back-end using REST API and OpenAPI specification for documentation.
- Covered implemented logic with unit tests using JUnit, Mockito, ensuring >80% code coverage.
- Covered implemented Rest API endpoints with end-to-end tests using the BDD framework Karate.
- Technologies: Java 17, Spring Framework (Boot, Data, Security, Webflux), Microservices, Hibernate, Gradle, Kubernetes, Docker, Terraform, Kafka, ELK, AWS, EC2, S3, Gitlab pipelines CI/CD, PostgreSQL, Flyway, Keycloak, Karate, OpenAPI.
- Links
 - https://symphony-solutions.com/project-hansecom
 - https://hansecom.com/en/solutions/mobility-platform.html

Etiya Inc. Lviv, Ukraine

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AT VIDEOTRON PROJECT

May 2021 - Dec 2021

- Developed new features for the business support system of a major Canadian telecom provider.
- Reduced API latency time by 45% for the key endpoint, from 15 to 8 seconds.
- Managed integration processes across various IT systems.
- Conducted maintenance and bug-fixing.
- Technologies: Java 8, Maven, Spring Framework (Boot, Data, Batch, Security) ActiveMQ, Jenkins
- · Links:
- https://www.etiya.com/en/insight/videotrons-transformation...

Webitel Lviv, Ukraine

SALES MANAGER

Feb. 2019 - Jan. 2021

- Made over \$500,000 in revenue as hunter role sales by providing contact center solution using Creatio CRM and Webitel IP Telephony
 as core software products.
- Managed and made a sale with the company from the Fortune 500 list.
- Managed sales for CIS, Europe, and the North America region. Expertise in Microfinance Organizations, Banking, Retail, and E-commerce markets.
- Achieved good personal reputation in partners network that led to receiving free inbound leads from recommendations.
- Developed new sales kit and strategies: presentations, key advantages, proof of concept, individual presentations, project road-maps.
- Took personal business trips with the team to support customer relationships and expand business opportunities.
- Represented the company and brought leads from conferences: Terrasoft Accelerate Global Conference, Kyiv Bank Online MFO Summit.
- Links:
 - https://www.webitel.com/
 - https://www.creatio.com/

Education _

Lviv Polytechnic National University

Lviv, Ukraine

PHD IN COMPUTER SCIENCE Oct. 2023 - Jul. 2024

- Stopped education because of relocation to the United Kingdom.
- Publications:
 - Developing a sentiment analyzer using ChatGPT for a stock market: https://doi.org/10.23939/cds2024.01.107

Lviv Polytechnic National University

Lviv, Ukraine

MASTERS'S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sep. 2021 - Dec. 2022

• Average rating: 77.88

Lviv Polytechnic National University

Lviv, Ukraine

BACHELOR'S IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

Sep. 2017 - Aug. 2021

- Organizing committee member of the 15th CADSM International Conference.
- Average rating: 81.15

Extracurricular Activity

EPAM Systems (Java Laboratory 28)

Lviv, Ukraine

STUDENT Nov. 2020 - May. 2021

- Gained Java Core theoretical knowledge and practical skills.
- Practice with JUnit, Mockito, JDBC, H2
- Implemented XML parsers: DOM, SAX, STAX
- Learned OOP, GRASP/SOLID principles and GoF design patterns in practice
- Developed personal web-project that helps in managing tests & questionnaires. Used Java servlets and JSP pages, without frameworks.
- Refactored back-end from Java servlets with commands design pattern to Spring application with Rest API.

Ternopil Without Problems Hackaton

Ternopil, Ukraine

PARTICIPANT

May. 2018

- Co-creator of the concept "AR Reproduction of the Destroyed Historical Architectural Heritage" to solve the tourism problem in Ternopil.
- Composed presentation and speech, presented the solution.

Personal Info.

HOBBIES

- FPV drones assemble.
- Creativity won 3rd place and 500 euros at Symphony's AI competition. Sponsored the next track of the "E-ho" rock band with the prize
 money.
 - Link: https://www.tiktok.com/@volodymyr.dorosh/video/7249842743697001734
- Fond of running and sports events took the 5th place in the Race Nation Bukovel running event, 21 km with 30 obstacles.